<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Ishaan Rawal</title>
    <link>https://israwal.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://israwal.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://israwal.github.io/media/icon_hue5d671e0b768c50a6d08d5b4f04cff0f_40307_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://israwal.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novel de-novo Short-Read Genome Assembler</title>
      <link>https://israwal.github.io/project/genome_assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://israwal.github.io/project/genome_assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: Ongoing (Since Jan 2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am working as a student researcher at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bits-pilani.ac.in/pilani/computerscience/AdvancedDataAnalyticsParallelTechnologiesLaboratory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Advanced Data Analytics and Parallel Technologies (ADAPT) Lab, BITS Pilani&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://universe.bits-pilani.ac.in/pilani/poonam/profile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Poonam Goyal&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequence_assembly&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sequence assemby&lt;/a&gt; is an NP-hard problem which can be modelled as a variant of string reconstruction problem. We are building a novel de-novo short-read genome assembler to reconstruct the contigs efficiently. The proposed assembler is being built with distributed and hierarchical data structures and using intermediaries, unitigs, to avoid the bottlenecks. We harness overlap and paired-end information along with some novel features to extend the unitigs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Video Reconstruction From Brain Activity</title>
      <link>https://israwal.github.io/project/brain_video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://israwal.github.io/project/brain_video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: Ongoing (Since Dec 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://userpage.fu-berlin.de/rmcichy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Radoslaw Martin Cichy&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ewi-psy.fu-berlin.de/en/einrichtungen/arbeitsbereiche/neural_dyn_of_vis_cog/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Neural Dynamics of Visual Cognition Lab&lt;/a&gt;, Freie Universität Berlin) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cvai.cs.uni-frankfurt.de/team.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Gemma Roig&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cvai.cs.uni-frankfurt.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Computer Vision and Artificial Intelligence Lab, Goethe University&lt;/a&gt;) to decode and reconstruct the features of natural videos from brain fMRI signals using Deep Learning. We are using Deep Neural Network activations as a proxy to map the fMRI features to the video space to decode, understand and compare the hierarchical and selective representation of features in the brain and neural network using activation maximization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis Of Long-Distance Linked Selection In Indian Variants Of SARS-CoV-2</title>
      <link>https://israwal.github.io/project/covid_genome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://israwal.github.io/project/covid_genome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: Completed (June 2020 - Sept 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was done during the fist wave of the COVID-19 pandemic, in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;http://arunsethuraman.weebly.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Arun Sethuraman&lt;/a&gt;, California State University, San Marcos. Long range mutations are not well studied in evolutionary biology. We hypothesized that associations in long-range mutations gives more reasons to inspect the causal influence of a set of mutations over another. Such association rules were mined using apriori algorithm and their individual stability was analyzed. This was the first ever data-driven analysis of viral long-range mutations. We presented our work at the virtual poster presentation at COVID-19 Dynamics and Evolution Virtual Conference, organised by UC San Diego School of Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intervertebral Disc Segmentation Using U-Net</title>
      <link>https://israwal.github.io/project/disc_segment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://israwal.github.io/project/disc_segment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: Completed (May 2020 - Jul 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was completed as my summer internship at &lt;a href=&#34;https://orthobiomech.ethz.ch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Laboratory for Orthopaedic Biomechanics&lt;/a&gt;, ETH Zurich, under the guidance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://biomech.ethz.ch/the-institute/people/person-detail.html?persid=172198&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Jonas Widmer&lt;/a&gt;. The project involved building an image segmentation component of a larger pipeline for automatic analysis of spine MRI to indentify spinal defects. I was involved in segmentation of intervertebral disc. I compared different variants of U-Net (viz. vanilla, skip connection, inception modules etc). The model achieved a dice score of 94.1% and the overall segmentation pipeline scored 91.8%, which is competent with the state-of-the-art apporoaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
